hello everyone welcome again to finn
advisor today we'll be doing a
fundamentals of icici lombard general
insurance we'll start with the insurance
industry and why does it look so
attractive
then we'll jump to company specifics how
does
icsl lombard look as an enterprise will
look at the overall financials we'll
also try to do
the valuation of the stock which is
generally quite complicated for
insurance industry stock
we'll do it in two ways price to book
and price to earnings and finally we'll
look at some of the key risk if we want
to invest
in this stock so this is going to be a
very interesting video if you are
looking to invest in insurance industry
so would request you to stay till the
end
now let's look at the insurance industry
for india and worldwide so generally
there are two dollars product life and
non-life insurance products non-life is
essentially your motor insurance health
insurance crop insurance fire insurance
so on and so forth and when we look at
the penetration in india it's roughly
about the total penetration is about
four percent where
the
life insurance is about three percent
and the non-life part is about one
percent and this is comparatively very
low when we compare it with the
developed countries most of these
countries have a total penetration of
above 10 percent be it us uk south korea
uk
and
for india to from from this level of 4
percent to reach above 10 penetration
there is a long headway for growth for
this insurance industry
now let's look at some of the industry
specific charts for the indian insurance
industry when we look at the trend of
premium underwritten so it has been
growing at a double digit pace over the
years last five years specifically
and
there are two different types of players
in the industry one is the public
players for example lic and then the
private players
even in the general insurance industry
other than the life insurance we have
four types of players the psus the
private
sector players
stand-alone health insurance players and
the specialized players
and roughly the overall market share for
the private and the other players has
been increasing over the years
while psu shares have been losing their
market shares over the years
when we look at the different segments
that are there in the general insurance
the most two important major segments
are the motor and the health insurance
and other than that there is fire
insurance marine and some of the other
insurance for example crop and so on and
so
in summary why should we even consider
insurance industry so like we discussed
there is a variation of non-life
insurance products in india about 0.97
of gdp
compared to the global average of around
2.3 percent so which provides a huge
potential to grow further in this
industry
the industry overall at a grew at a
seizure of seventeen percent in the last
two decades and this is expected to
continue
further in the coming years
even the private sector market share has
risen from 15 to 49.3
in
last 17 years
fdi limit in insurance sector has
increased from 49 to 74 percent which
should result in higher investment
foreign investment in this space
corona pandemic has also changed the
landspeak
especially for the products such as
health insurance there is an increased
amount of awareness
for these kind of protection products
some of the other aspects such as
urbanization and demographic aspects
such as
rising middle class increasing financial
literacy amongst millennials
these are significant
drivers for growth of insurance
now let's look at
the company specific for icici lombard
so it has been a target leader
since fy 2004 it is a leading private
sector for non-life insurers
the cagr for last 13 years is close to
market share after its recent merger
with bharti excise close to 8.3
it has a diverse product portfolio and a
multi-channel distribution off plate it
has been focusing on increasing the
distribution network in tier three and
tier four where the scope of growth is
higher
it has a digital arm specific for
technology so
very focused on technology
very product risk management team and
also in terms of capital
conservation
uh it has maintained a solution of 2.45
x compared to a minimum requirement of
around 1.56
when we look at the product mix of
icsc lombard because it has a very
diversified product portfolio
covering motor health travel personal
accident fire marine crop and others
uh the majority part of the product
portfolio about 44
is in the motor
in 22 in the third party and 22 percent
in the own damage
by the next top segment is the health
travel and personal accident
while fire constitutes about 17
icsc lombard has focused a lot on the
digitization in initiatives that is the
main reason why it has now the lowest
expense ratio in the industry
due to continuous digitization when we
look at some of the
in specific initiatives that it has
taken in policy issues about 97.2
percent
uh policies have been issued
electronically
in claims and servicing about 80 percent
of the motor od claims were done through
insta aspect
even in the headcount productivity there
is a 15 cagr
from fy 2008 to
2021.
it has also done a cloud deployment
and a big data and customer experience
management
in even in ai nml solutions
uh
66.4 percent are done through cashless
authorization
to ai
while 85.3
percent of stp motor breaking was done
through self inspection
so and it has also has a dynamic
workforce with remote working policy
so overall
it has done a lot in terms of
digitization and it continues further to
improve efficiency
to reduce the
even in risk management icse lombard has
done quite well
in underwriting it has initiated
predictive loss model
diversified exposure across geographies
and
also has a lower proportion of losses
during catastrophic events
it has also spread the risk across panel
of quality reinsurance
reduces the overall risk even in terms
of
reporting it has been disclosing the
reserving triangles which talks a lot
about corporate governance and
transparency
in investments
it has
about 90 percent of the portfolio in
debt which is on triple a rated
securities it has almost zero instance
of default
since its inception which is quite
exceptional
in this kind of scenario
when we look at the financials for ics
lombard one of the key ratio that is low
insurance sector is the combined ratio
ratio which is less than 100
signifies that
the claims incurred and the expenses
the company was able to manage within
the premiums
that were received for the insurance
so ideally it should be less than 100
but due to corona pandemic the
combined ratio has should
shoot enough
uh about 120 to 125 percent it is for
the industry and while for isis is
lombard it is about 111
this has taken a hit on both the profit
before tax and the profit after tax
going down for this year
but as the pandemic settles this the
profit and other metrics should again
come to normal the return on equity has
been on the higher side more than 15 in
some cases more than 20 percent this
should again go up
as the impact due to pandemics comes
down
when we look at the investment book
uh the return that
the
investment book has been able to get is
about six shot percent
about 90 percent of the portfolio is in
the
corporate balance and the government
security the investment book roughly is
growing about 20
on an average over the years which is a
really good growth rate
one for this size
now let's look at the valuation for icsa
lombard generally valuations needed for
insurance stock
different people have different opinion
how should a company be valued in
insurance sector i've made two attempts
in using price to book and price to
earning let's first look at price to
book so when we look at the historical
graph and the current valuation in terms
of price to book historically the median
price to book that i say says lombard
has been able to get is somewhere close
to
8.5 now given that there are higher
claims ratio and
the higher claims that has been incurred
due to corona pandemic
the profitability has come down
for short term
and now the price to book has come
somewhere around 6.5 so based on the
median valuation it definitely looks
undervalued at this point of time
now let's deep dive further and try to
estimate the bull base and beer case
scenarios using book value
so currently we are sitting at the
levels of 12 45 historical book value
growth rate that we've seen over the
years is roughly about 20 percent
and
let's assume in bull case the book value
will grow at 22 percent in base case the
book value will grow at 17 and
beer case it will grow at 15 so these
are the
values
assuming these growth percentages
in fy 25 in bull case let's assume that
the price to book multiple i say lombard
will be able to get would be around 12
base case would be 10 and your case
would be 7.
based on this if we multiply
these figures with these
we'll be able to get the fy 25 stock
price which will range between 2000 to
from
their case to base
full case
which results about stock price x of
about 1.6 to 3.3 times and a stock price
area of 21 to 78
and please bear in mind this is
definitely not a recommendation this
video has been made from educational
point of view
now let's try to estimate
the valuation for ics lombard using
price to earn try to estimate the
earnings
till fy25
and there are two types of earnings
operating
and non-operating operating is from all
the products insurance products that icc
lombard has
so premium earned it has been assumed to
grow at about 15
investment income is again from the
policyholders fund
this has been again assumed to grow at
about 15 to 20 percent and it will be
able to
get a need of about six percent
yeah the main assumption in terms of
underwriting profit losses that it will
normalize
currently it is quite high due to covet
pandemic and this will normalize to
about a 104 percent of combined ratio
and this will result in a nominal five
percent underwriting loss on the premium
earned
and the investment income will continue
to grow both from the policyholders and
from the shareholders so this will
result in pad to grow significantly
till fy 25 and the eps will grow to
about
69 from till fy 25
and
if we assume
three different scenario for what would
be the price to earning multiple that
icici lombard will be able to get in fbi
25 let's assume
60 for bulk case 50 base and 44 beer
that means if we multiply this eps of 69
with
these p multiples the price could range
between 2700 to 4100
between all these cases
now let's look at some of the key risks
uh for icsa lombard if you win this
stock
first key risk is with respect to kovit
19 this has resulted in high loss ratios
if we see a new variant
which is seems a bit unlikely at this
moment but if we see a new variant
we
still have
we still may have lesser profitability
for the short term
icc lombard also has very high
dependence on auto sector about 44
of the product portfolio is comprised of
the motor
and this industry is facing a lot of
competition in terms of themes and also
there are industry headwinds
with respect to chip shortage which has
resulted in lesser
new private car sales
and there are also talks of about the
terrification of the third party
uh product which is about 22 of
the icici
lombard portfolio
and this can result in price water and
industry pressure and uh reduced product
suitability for icc number
uh icc lombard has also a lagging health
care portfolio given that it was one of
the first entrants
if we would have hoped that it would
become a market leader but there are
other players who have taken significant
amount of
market share in the healthcare
that's all i wanted to cover in icsa
lombard fundamental analysis hope it was
useful to you and if you like this video
please do subscribe to the channel and
share with your family and friends
hope to see you in my next video